<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<channel>
		<title>Joseph Petitti's Blog</title>
		<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog</link>
		<description>This blog is a collection of random opinions and ramblings on a variety of topics including programming, software, films, and the great outdoors.</description>
			<image>
				<url>https://josephpetitti.com/images/logo.png</url>
				<title>Joseph Petitti's Blog</title>
				<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog</link>
			</image>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<atom:link href="https://josephpetitti.com/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			<title>The underrated brilliance of American Psycho</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-underrated-brilliance-of-american-psycho</link>
			<description>I've seen a lot of movies, and Mary Harron's 2000 psychological thriller American Psycho is one of my favorites of all time. Yet for some reason it seems like this masterpiece has mostly flown under the radar, seen as a curious but shallow origin of memes, and remembered with a casual "oh yeah, that was alright." This lack of acclaim for a film I rank among the likes of 2001: A Space Odyssey and The End of Evangelion is great injustice in my eyes, so I will try to explain what I like so much about it. Be warned, there be spoilers here, so for the best experience go watch the film first and come up with your own explanations, then come back and read this.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-underrated-brilliance-of-american-psycho</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Audica and Beat Saber: how to do early access right and wrong</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/audica-and-beat-saber-how-to-do-early-access-right-and-wrong</link>
			<description>Very rarely do you get such a perfect case study handed to you as with Audica and Beat Saber. Both are early access VR rhythm games on Steam and Oculus, both involve hitting red and blue notes with the correctly-colored weapon carried in each of you hands, and both are damn good fun. Let's take a look at how Audica takes advantage of early access to push content to early adopters while Beat Saber takes advantage of early access to take advantage of users.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/audica-and-beat-saber-how-to-do-early-access-right-and-wrong</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Exploring the Shinichirō Watanabe Cinematic Universe</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/exploring-the-shinichiro-watanabe-cinematic-universe</link>
			<description>Director Shinichirō Watanabe is well known for his science fiction and fantasy anime worlds filled with memorable characters, creative technology, and wonderous adventures. It appears that three of his critically acclaimed series, Cowboy Bebop, Space Dandy, and Carole &amp; Tuesday take place in the same universe, but the truth is much more complicated than that.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/exploring-the-shinichiro-watanabe-cinematic-universe</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Meet the Cloud Office: the workplace of the future</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/meet-the-cloud-office-the-workplace-of-the-future</link>
			<description>Nobody wants to deal with the hassle of maintaining hardware. It's expensive, difficult, and time consuming to set up your own networked infrastructure, and many companies just aren't dealing with it any more. But as more and more of our computer systems are transitioned into the cloud, we could end up in a world where the office as we know it is obsolete.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/meet-the-cloud-office-the-workplace-of-the-future</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Adventures in system administration - Part 1</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-1</link>
			<description>Part 1 of an ongoing guide documenting my process of setting up a virtual network of servers to host various services for me</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-1</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>How to change Wordpress URLs in the database</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-change-wordpress-urls-in-the-database</link>
			<description>Wordpress has a nasty habit of redirecting you to what it thinks the correct domain name is, and this value is hidden in multiple obscure places in the database. If you've ever had to migrate a Wordpress site from one domain name to another you've probably encountered this problem. Fortunately, there is a relatively painless way to reconfigure Wordpress to use the new domain name from inside its database.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-change-wordpress-urls-in-the-database</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Adventures in system administration - Part 2</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-2</link>
			<description>Part 2 of an ongoing series about setting up a network of virtual servers. In this post, we configure Foreman and and a virtual network to allow unattended creation and provisioning of virtual hosts.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 5 Jun 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-2</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>How to toggle styles on click in pure CSS</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-toggle-styles-on-click-in-pure-css</link>
			<description>There are plenty of times in front-end web development where you want to toggle between two different CSS rules when an element is clicked. Maybe you want a custom menu to drop down, or a set of tabs to show different information. Either way, you could do this with some simple JavaScript. Or, you could use a CSS hack to do it without any scripts at all.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-toggle-styles-on-click-in-pure-css</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>My top 10 favorite research papers</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/my-top-10-favorite-research-papers</link>
			<description>Some of the most amusing or intriguing studies, reports, and scientific papers I've stumbled across</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/my-top-10-favorite-research-papers</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Four days in Seoul</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/four-days-in-seoul</link>
			<description>After an exhausting 44-hour journey involving planes, trains, and automobiles, I arrived in Seoul, South Korea this past Sunday. I'll be spending the next three months in Kyoto, Japan working on my Major Qualifying Project for WPI, but before that I wanted to spend some time seeing another city I had never been to before.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/four-days-in-seoul</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Thoughts on Japan</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/thoughts-on-japan</link>
			<description>As I mentioned in my last blog post, I'm spending three months in Japan to work on my Major Qualifying Project, a graduation requirement of WPI. Now that I've been here for almost four weeks I can talk a bit about what Japan is like, and my experiences here.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/thoughts-on-japan</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Japanese rhythm games: my new addiction</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/japanese-rhythm-games-my-new-addiction</link>
			<description>I've written previously about my love of Audica and Beat Saber but those aren't the only rhythm games I play. I used to be pretty good at Guitar Hero, and I've recently gotten into Stepmania. However, studying in Japan has introduced me to the magical world of Japanese arcade rhythm games, a new class of game that is threatening to consume all my money.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:00:16 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/japanese-rhythm-games-my-new-addiction</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Fuji-Q Highland: proof that you can make a theme park out of anything</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/fuji-q-highland-proof-that-you-can-make-a-theme-park-out-of-anything</link>
			<description>This weekend I traveled across Japan to climb Mount Fuji, the highest mountain in the country and one of the most beautiful and recognizable mountains in the world. But before starting the climb, three fellow students and I spent a night in Fujiyoshida, Yamanashi to go to Fuji-Q Highland, a Mount Fuji-themed amusement park.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 13:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/fuji-q-highland-proof-that-you-can-make-a-theme-park-out-of-anything</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>How to climb Mount Fuji</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-climb-mount-fuji</link>
			<description>Last week, after spending a day at Fuji-Q Highland, I set out with a group of three other students to climb to the highest point in Japan, the summit of Mount Fuji.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 09:49:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-climb-mount-fuji</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Leap seconds are actually a terrible idea</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/leap-seconds-are-actually-a-terrible-idea</link>
			<description>About once every four years the powers that be slide an extra day into the calendar between February 28th and March 1st, to ensure that our timekeeping system stays in sync with the actual rotation of the Earth. We call this a leap year, and the current system of deciding when to add these extra days has remained unchanged for the past 437 years. However, recently Coordinated Universal Time has started adding leap seconds to particular years as well, a phenomenon which is causing all sorts of trouble for timekeeping around the world.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 06:34:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/leap-seconds-are-actually-a-terrible-idea</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Quines in JavaScript</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/quines-in-javascript</link>
			<description>Because programmers have nothing better to do with their free time, they often amuse themselves by finding clever solutions to difficult logic problems. One such problem is called a "quine," and it goes something like this: write the shortest possible program the prints its own source code.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 07:31:16 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/quines-in-javascript</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>How to take beautiful notes with Pandoc</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-take-beautiful-notes-with-pandoc</link>
			<description>Taking notes by hand is so old fashioned. You can't version control or backup paper, it's hard to search through, and a small mistake can force you to cross out or erase a whole line of text. But taking good notes on a computer has a host of problems of its own. Fiddling with formatting and typesetting is time-consuming, and it's hard to include mathematical notation, images, and other elements that are easy to write by hand but hard to type. Fortunately, I've found a solution that's easy and fun to use: writing Markdown and compiling it to a LaTeX-produced PDF with Pandoc. Read on to learn how I do it.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 07:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-take-beautiful-notes-with-pandoc</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>The C ??!??! operator</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-c-%3F%3F!%3F%3F!-operator</link>
			<description> The C programming language has a bit of a reputation for having weird syntax. The #define directive, pointer declaration, and uncommon array indexing methods can all make it hard to understand what's going on in a C program. Still, some of C's weirdness manages to surprise me even after using it for a few years. For example, what do you think this expression does: !x ??!??! y();</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 18:53:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-c-%3F%3F!%3F%3F!-operator</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Making a simple text-based game in C++</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/making-a-simple-text-based-game-in-c++</link>
			<description>For the WPI course IMGD 3000 - Technical Game Development 1, I worked over the course of seven weeks to make a fully-featured game engine in C++. It uses simple text-based ASCII graphics and handles events, input, sounds, sprites, collisions, and other basic features. As a final project, to show off the features of this engine, I worked with a partner to make a fun game using it. The game, called "XiQ", is a fast-paced arcade puzzle game in based on the Taito classic Qix.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2019 02:47:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/making-a-simple-text-based-game-in-c++</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
