<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<channel>
		<title>Joseph Petitti's Blog</title>
		<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog</link>
		<description>This blog is a collection of random opinions and ramblings on a variety of topics including programming, software, films, and the great outdoors.</description>
			<image>
				<url>https://josephpetitti.com/images/logo.png</url>
				<title>Joseph Petitti's Blog</title>
				<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog</link>
			</image>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<atom:link href="https://josephpetitti.com/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			<title>The underrated brilliance of American Psycho</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-underrated-brilliance-of-american-psycho</link>
			<description>I've seen a lot of movies, and Mary Harron's 2000 psychological thriller American Psycho is one of my favorites of all time. Yet for some reason it seems like this masterpiece has mostly flown under the radar, seen as a curious but shallow origin of memes, and remembered with a casual "oh yeah, that was alright." This lack of acclaim for a film I rank among the likes of 2001: A Space Odyssey and The End of Evangelion is great injustice in my eyes, so I will try to explain what I like so much about it. Be warned, there be spoilers here, so for the best experience go watch the film first and come up with your own explanations, then come back and read this.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 18:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/the-underrated-brilliance-of-american-psycho</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Audica and Beat Saber: how to do early access right and wrong</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/audica-and-beat-saber-how-to-do-early-access-right-and-wrong</link>
			<description>Very rarely do you get such a perfect case study handed to you as with Audica and Beat Saber. Both are early access VR rhythm games on Steam and Oculus, both involve hitting red and blue notes with the correctly-colored weapon carried in each of you hands, and both are damn good fun. Let's take a look at how Audica takes advantage of early access to push content to early adopters while Beat Saber takes advantage of early access to take advantage of users.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 23:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/audica-and-beat-saber-how-to-do-early-access-right-and-wrong</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Exploring the Shinichirō Watanabe Cinematic Universe</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/exploring-the-shinichiro-watanabe-cinematic-universe</link>
			<description>Director Shinichirō Watanabe is well known for his science fiction and fantasy anime worlds filled with memorable characters, creative technology, and wonderous adventures. It appears that three of his critically acclaimed series, Cowboy Bebop, Space Dandy, and Carole &amp; Tuesday take place in the same universe, but the truth is much more complicated than that.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 18:30:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/exploring-the-shinichiro-watanabe-cinematic-universe</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Meet the Cloud Office: the workplace of the future</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/meet-the-cloud-office-the-workplace-of-the-future</link>
			<description>Nobody wants to deal with the hassle of maintaining hardware. It's expensive, difficult, and time consuming to set up your own networked infrastructure, and many companies just aren't dealing with it any more. But as more and more of our computer systems are transitioned into the cloud, we could end up in a world where the office as we know it is obsolete.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 20:26:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/meet-the-cloud-office-the-workplace-of-the-future</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Adventures in system administration - Part 1</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-1</link>
			<description>Part 1 of an ongoing guide documenting my process of setting up a virtual network of servers to host various services for me</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 21:44:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/adventures-in-system-administration-part-1</guid>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>How to change Wordpress URLs in the database</title>
			<link>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-change-wordpress-urls-in-the-database</link>
			<description>Wordpress has a nasty habit of redirecting you to what it thinks the correct domain name is, and this value is hidden in multiple obscure places in the database. If you've ever had to migrate a Wordpress site from one domain name to another you've probably encountered this problem. Fortunately, there is a relatively painless way to reconfigure Wordpress to use the new domain name from inside its database.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 16:42:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid>https://josephpetitti.com/blog/how-to-change-wordpress-urls-in-the-database</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
